

#### EMBEDDED SOFTWARE ENGINEER

473 West Happfield Drive, Arlington Heights, IL

□ 682-241-8753 | 

□ knguyen2133@qmail.com | □ knguyen2133 | □ knguyen2133

# **Professional Summary**.

Embedded Software Engineer with five years of professional experience with interest in dealing with embedded systems. Proficiency in developing software in the driver level. Including, leading teams during integration and testing. Highly value and have experience in software development life-cycles, communication, and constructive feedback.

## **Experience**

Northrop Grumman Rolling Meadows, Illinois

EMBEDDED SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Integrate kernel modules communication over multiple SBCs and sensors (I<sup>2</sup>C, PCIE)
- · Develop camera tracking software
- Work with cross compilation between architectures for development (ARM, x86\_64)
- Setup networks and embedded Linux environments (RedHat, Yocto)
- · Assisted multiple departments in documentation, design, and testing
- Managed version control and agile development (Atlassian)
- Coded mainly in C++ and C

### **L&T Technology Services Limited**

Peoria, Illinois

Nov. 2019 - Present

May 2018 - Nov 2019

EMBEDDED SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- · Contracted to multiple companies for Development and Verification: Collins Aerospace, John Deere
- Manage requirements under DO-178C standards
- Produce/Modify test scripts for CAN Protocol verification (Python, Bash, C)
- Facilitate version control (Mercurial)
- Document reports for changes in DOORS requirements and source code

Ayoka Systems Arlington, Texas

EMBEDDED/WEB DEVELOPER

Jul. 2017 - May 2018

- Develop software for microcontrollers that require RTOS features
- Worked in embedded Linux environment (Debian)
- Assist in communication between microcontrollers and upload to Amazon S3 (RF, UART, SPI, I<sup>2</sup>C, Wifi)
- Experience Validation/Verification process with clients
- Initially intern for six months experiencing

Analyze projects for technical faults

**Unit Testing** 

Manage repositories (Github)

## **Skills**

**Programming** C++, C, Python, Bash, Git, Java

Operating Systems RedHat, Yocto, Debian
Comm Protocols I<sup>2</sup>C, PCIE, SPI, UART, BLE, RF
Microcontrollers Raspberry Pi, Arduino, TI

**Processors** ARM, x86\_64, TI **Languages** English

## Education \_

**Class Projects** 

#### **University of Texas at Arlington**

Arlington, Texas

Aug. 2014 - May 2018

## Extracurricular Activities \_

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING

#### **Software Senior Design Project**

University of Texas at Arlington

University of Texas at Arlington

- · Assemble a smart shoe that displays images on an E-ink screen via BLE using a nRF52 chip that was sponsored under Bioworld
- Required agile development

Designed an alarm system that triggers based on motion or temperature
Built a TRISC that read instructions on RAM

Environment Sensor Recreational

· Programmed TI microcontrollers to transfer temperature, ambient, and humidity data through RF communication

January 22, 2022 Kevin Nguyen · Résumé